<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-07-27T22:52:18+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Marty’s blog</title><subtitle></subtitle><author><name>Maarten van Elst</name></author><entry><title type="html">Round 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/07/27/round-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Round 3" /><published>2022-07-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-07-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/07/27/round-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/07/27/round-3.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;round-3-of-classical-heavy-chemo&quot;&gt;Round 3 of ‘classical heavy chemo’&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve some energy left, so here is a quick blog post before bed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I received my third dosage of the ABVD chemotherapy scheme, after a week of giving my bone marrow some rest. This rest was a required a bit earlier than expected, but well… One of my doctors referred to ABVD as &lt;em&gt;classical heavy chemo&lt;/em&gt;, which might explain that. TBH classical heavy chemo is definitely not as bad as I imgagined. So far this whole charade (sometimes it feels like that) has been very doable with support from my parents, family, and good friends. To summarize:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Progress in beating cancer (current estimate):
|##########------------------------------|25%
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to undergo a grand total of 4 dosages before a PET scan in August where we will learn whether classical heavy chemo is effective. There’s only 1 confirmed and 3 probably malignant lymph nodes in my chest left, so the doctor says there’s a good chance that the scan might even be clean or that there is little activity left in these 4 assholes. I really hope this is the case, because it is a solid step towards recovery and because it means we get to use lighter drugs for the 4 remaining months of classical heavy chemo. &lt;em&gt;yay!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amazing thing about being relatively young and dealing with chemotherapy is that you don’t notice the side effects as much as they tell you to expect. I really feel that my body is resilient to the effects. Initial tiredness and nausea aside, and the slowly going bald part isn’t great. But from what I’ve read online us youngsters seem to get through it all pretty well. My own experience so far confirms this, fingers crossed it stays that way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m definitely able to enjoy summer for a bit. I just spent the most amazing weekend in a town called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sneek&quot;&gt;Sneek&lt;/a&gt; last week. Especially the warm and sunny sunday on a boat with friends of the family - to be away from it all was a great mental pick-me-up. It’s nice being out on the water looking at other (sailing) boats and nature. Even more so with un-dutch-near-mediterranean temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I might add some photos below once I get ‘post security’ working (still working on the ‘how to build this blog’ entry). But good night for now :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Maarten van Elst</name></author><category term="hodgkin" /><summary type="html">Round 3 of ‘classical heavy chemo’ I’ve some energy left, so here is a quick blog post before bed.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/07/14/First.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First!" /><published>2022-07-14T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-07-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/07/14/First</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/07/14/First.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-is-about-time-to-write-a-first-blog-post&quot;&gt;It is about time to write a first blog post.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of this first post is to flesh out what I want to do in this blog (pretty meta, you should see the ‘how to build a blog’ post that’s in the pipeline). Thing is, I’ve been thinking about what exactly to put in this blog for a while… usually when I need to write away my frustrations I sit down at my laptop and write in text files for myself. They contain what I would call “emotional life stuff”, and I keep them in a very secret folder. Usually I’m not very sober when writing these little snippets. Rest assured, this high-brow literature will never see the light of the world wide web. Hopefully by writing a blog this process becomes more structured, almost &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt; for future me and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve got big plans.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is that this blog is a place to gather results of all the distractions I undertake while dealing with something quite awful: Hodgkin’s disease (more on that in another post). There’ll be your usual updates on how I’m doing for friends and family, the thoughts I have and things I struggle (or don’t struggle) with. These will be posts like this one where I write mostly for myself. I also have quite some time on my hands the rest of 2022 and it would be great if I can keep busy - with something to show for it in the form of a blog post. Programming projects, making music, maybe finally reading a book and so on. Posts will be labeled with tags, and some of them might be private (i.e. password protected). Aside from disease updates and my rambling there could be sections on music, computers, maybe biology and/or machine learning, books, gaming - let’s see how this develops, eh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As it turns out, ‘big plans’ can be summarized in one paragraph&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also my attempt at getting familiar with the feeling of writing for online publication. The great thing about a blog is that you can say it’s a place “for me, by me”, but that feels like cheaping out. The whole point here is to move away from writing just for yourself. If &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; want to, please share your genuine thoughts :). I don’t think of myself as a good writer, my thoughts often change directions while trying to put something &lt;del&gt;to paper&lt;/del&gt; in text. But I like to think I’m okay at receiving criticism, so bring it on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phew. Quite the threshold taken today. This site is now online, and here’s your first post - I hope it’s… A start :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Maarten van Elst</name></author><category term="misc" /><category term="hodgkin" /><summary type="html">It is about time to write a first blog post.</summary></entry></feed>